Guide to the Charles Haupter papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Charles Haupter papers,
1900-1947
Haupter, Charles L.
1.5 linear ft. (3 document boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
MS#1607
6910556
Papers and war time diary of Charles Haupter, journalist, businessman and employee of the Office of War Information during World War II.
Biographical Note
Charles L. Haupter was educated at the City College of New York and Brooklyn College, where he studied engineering in the late 1920s.
In 1944, at the height of World War II, Haupter took a job with the Office of War Information, a U.S. governmental agency the distributed news and information about the war and managed the U.S. propaganda campaign. Haupter worked in New York and London as a radio operator and news writer for the OWI.
At the end of the war Haupter returned to the United States and opened a business, Central Office Service, in Younkers New York.
Scope and Content
Collection is comprised primarily of daily news bulletins released by a number of sources that Haupter collected throughout World War II as part of his position in the United States Office of War Information. Also included in the collection are his personal diary for 1944, starting with him taking his position with the OWI, and some records related to his business interests after the war.
Arrangement
Material is organized into two series
Series I: Personal Material, 1900-1947
Series II: World War II Material, 1943-1946
Subjects
United States.--Office of War Information.; World War, 1939-1945
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
Haupter Family Gift 11/30/1992
- Series I: Personal Material, 1900-1947
  - Haupter Family Papers, 1900-1928 (Box 1)
  - Charles Haupter College Coursework, 1927-1928 (Box 1)
    (City College of New York and Brooklyn College Engineering and Calculus Exercises)
  - Haupter's Writings-- Poetry and Parodies (Box 1)
  - Central Office Service Records, 1947 (Box 1)
- Series II: World War II Material, 1943-1946
  - Haupter's Diary, 1944 (Box 1)
    (from his time in the Office of War Information, stationed in New York and London)
  - News Releases and Bulletins (Box 2)
    - BBC Digest of World News, 1945 (Box 2)
    - BBC News Information Service Weeks Anniversaries Bulletin (Box 2)
    - Radio News-- Supreme Allied Expeditionary Forces, 1945 (Box 2)
    - News Release Published Aboard the U.S.A.T. Admiral Rodman, 1946 (Box 2)
    - Ministry of Information News Bulletins, 1943-1945 (Box 2)
    - United Nations Review, 1943-1944 (Box 2)
    - Soviet Radio Bulletins (Box 2)
    - Soviet Radio Bulletins, (5 Folders) (Box 3)